So, a hypothesis was put forward that the form of the oscillogram on the transistor drains.
Due to this IR2113 driver not handling its work well, there's some interference in the gate.
Capacitance.
And that's why the transistor produces such spikes.
Let's look now.
This is the signal on the transistor gates.
Signal is clear, the system power isn't on right now.
So, here's our power.
Right now consumption is zero.
I'm closing the jumper between the batteries.
We see, there's consumption, power has gone.
Look at the oscillogram shape.
As we see, the oscillogram practically hasn't changed.
Edges are clear, only at the bottom small ripple was added in this part from static pickup.
Now we'll look.
Decreasing the duty cycle.
We see that at any duty cycle the driver clearly holds the edge and no interference is observed in the gate capacitance.
Decreasing duty cycle more.
That is, the driver works great, doesn't produce any interference.
System is on, everything's normal.
Now I'll switch the blue channel to the transistor drain, where there's the static spike.
Remove the amplitude trace and look.
Yellow channel is our gate control of this transistor, blue is the spike on the drain.
Adding duty cycle.
Duty cycle goes.
Good signal edge.
Now we'll bring it to optimal operating mode.
Here it is, the optimal mode.
Sets in when our duty cycle is 41%.
We see, here's our control and here's our signal.
No interference in the gate for us.
This process goes purely in this core with gaps.
For those interested, here's the schematic by which this driver is connected.
Here's its wiring schematic.
Here I specifically noted what else can be done with this driver.
Very interesting moment.
If you feed 5V to the 9th pin through a regulator, this driver will be compatible with 5V logic.
And here, if we feed high supply potential to pin 11, both channels will be disabled.
On this driver this way you can make system protection.
Once more the schematic.